A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Projects FA733
Rockefeller Archive Center
- D-935: Stanford Research Institute - Program of research and technical assistance on international development problems, 1963 (Reel P-1036)
- D-936: Foundation for International Trade Research - Program of research on major problems and policy issues in the foreign trade of the United States, 1963 (Reel P-1036)
- D-937: Vocational and Technical Education (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1036, Reel P-1037)
- D-938: Purdue University - Visiting program for distinguished engineers, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-943: Union Theological Seminary - Program for advanced religious studies, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-945: Red Bank Public Schools (New Jersey) - Assistance in meeting the needs of pupils in a small school district, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-946: Development of Improved Procedures for Selecting Students from Underdeveloped Countries Coming to the United States for Graduate Training in Economics (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-947: University of Southern California - Develop and demonstrate a general purpose, regional health information center, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-953: Goddard College - Expirement in orienting the college curriculum to social goals, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-962: Hiram College - Elementary teaching internship program, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-963: Government of India, Ministry of Home Affairs - Indian vital statistics program, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-967: University of Chicago - Urban planning for public officials program, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-968: University of Chicago - Program for mayors and councilmen, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-969: University of Chicago - Regional intergovernmental cooperation program, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-970: International Association of Chiefs of Police, Inc. - Police executive development program, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-971: Government of India - Primate research institute, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-972: Latin American Studies (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-973: Government of Kenya - Establishment of an ethnographic project at the Coryndon Museum, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-974: Research on Professional Practice Overseas (Ford Foundation overseas), 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-975: Training in Economics for Students from Overseas (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-976: Gokhale Institute of Politics and Economics (India) - Institutional support for expansion of social science research and training, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-977: American Political Science Association - Educational program for visitors to the nation's capital, 1963 (Reel P-1037)
- D-979: European Association of Management Training Centers - Preparation of Instructors for Management Centers in Developing Countries, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-980: Inquiry into Intelligent Subjugation of Jungle Areas (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-981: Program Specialists and Consultants for Cultural Affairs (India field office), 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-983: Mercy College (Detroit, Michigan) - Pre-college summer session program, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-985: Cooperative Research and Experimentation on the Administration of Justice and Legal Services (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-987: National University of Colombia, Bogota - Assistance for geography development, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-996: McGill University - Development of engineering program, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- D-997: Syracuse University - Educational program in electrical engineering, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-3: Society for Advancement of Management, Inc. - Foundation for management education, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-6: University of Miami - Training Latin American law teachers in the United States and comparative law, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-10: American Heritage Foundation - Program to expand and strengthen the electoral process in our free society, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-15: Sanford University - Exchange of scholars in the field of organic chemistry with Brazil, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-16: University of Notre Dame - Population studies, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-25: Louisville Human Relations Commission (Kentucky) - Study on racial housing in Louisville, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-26: Advanced School of Public Administration of Colombia - Support for research in political science and public administration, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-27: Brookings Institution - Advisory and training services in support of the research center at the Advanced School of Public Administration (Colombia), 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-30: University of Windsor - Establishment of an instiute of Canadian-American studies, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-32: University of Chicago - New cirriculum leading to the doctoral degree in history, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-34: University of Florida, College of Medicine (Gainesville) - Support for studies in various aspects of reproduction, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-36: Center for Latin American Monetary Studies (CEMLA) - Extension of training activities, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-40: McMaster University - development plan, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-41: Purdue University - Research related to the encouragement of economic growth, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-54: University of Texas - Graduate education for urban administrators, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-55: Oresunds Hospital (Denmark) - Establishment of a laboratory of reproductive physiology, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-57: Programs of summer study at a few leading institutions for professional self-improvement of engineering faculty members from other institutions (Ford Foundation initiated), 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-61: University of Notre Dame - Research aspects of mammalian reproduction, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-62: University of Georgia - Establishment of a southeastern center for research into factors determining economic growth, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-63: Universities International House Appeal - Establish an international house on each campus: University of Sydney and University of New South Wales, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-65: United Nations Educational Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) - Evaluation of the major project of primary education in Latin America, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-67: Federal Housing Administration, Milwaukee, Wisconsin - Experimental home maintenace project, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-69: Tuskegee Institute - Seminar-conferences on developments in the elimination of disadvantage for all Americans, particular concern for the needs of Negroes, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-70: University of Oklahoma - Journalism field study program on Latin American affairs, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-73: Johns Hopkins University - Comparative case studies of development strategies for several low income economies, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-75: Canadian Philosophical Association - Inter-American philosophical congress, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-81: University of Pittsburgh - Training program to improve the management of development programs and projects, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-84: Milwaukee School of Engineering - Increase the availability of technically trained engineering personnel for industry, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-89: Carnegie Endowment for International Peace - Program in international law, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-90: Institute of Current World Affairs, Inc. - Fellowship program in Latin America, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-97: International Marketing Institute - Entrepreneurial training and economic growth, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-98: University of Texas - Experimental program of journalism education for the reporting and interpreting of public affairs, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-101: Ateneo de Manila University - Matching grant for chemistry building, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-102: Canadian Peace Research Institute - Support for peace research abstracts, 1963-1964 (Reel P-1038)
- E-104: Indiana University - Transfer of information form governmental research programs to business firms, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-109: City of Pontiac, Michigan - Systematic use of social organization knowledge to achieve neighborhood urban renewal goals, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-110: National Council of Women of the United States - International travel fund, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-111: Southern Association of Colleges and Schools - Improvement of educational quality in Latin America, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-115: Science Association of Nigeria - Directory of scientific and learned associations of Nigeria, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-116: University of North Carolina - Research on design and industrialized construction of complex communities under the conditions of a country in process of development, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-118: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn - Program for education of negro students, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-119: Pennsylvania State University - Professional development of engineering technology teachers, 1963 (Reel P-1038)
- E-120: National Society for the Study of Communication - Pilot national communication institute, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-126: Indiana University - Symposium on the place of language and language study in American life and education, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-129: University of the Andes, Bogota, Colombia - Study of economic research institutions of Latin America, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-132: International House of Japan - Interpretation of Japan and its culture, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-133: California Youth and Adult Corrections Agency - Exploratory study of the role of state government in youth development, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-134: African-American Institute - Inventory of educational and related assistance programs already established or intended for French speaking Africa, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-138: University of Pennsulvania - Summer institute on computer-matematics, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-143: University of Texas - Development of a theoretical framework for marketing decisions in comparative marketing, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-144: Council for the Study of Mankind - Program of research and education on the idea of mankind, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-146: Syracuse University - Research on the design image for the city, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-148: Modern Language Association of America - Chinese language information center, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-151: University of Louisville - Summer course for European and African teachers of English, 1963-1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-152: California Medical Education and Research Foundation - Medical care for the migratory agricultural-worker population in California, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-153: University of Hawaii - Confernece on race relations in Honolulu in the summer of 1965, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-154: Association for Cultural Exchange - Survey of the 28 Jesuit colleges and universities in the United States, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-156: University of British Columbia - Development of an experimental college, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-157: American Institute of Physics - Assistance in building the Niels Bohr Library of the History of Physics, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-158: Johns Hopkins University - Undergraduate-Graduate program in international affairs, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-159: Texas Christian University - Management cases with behavioral science annotations, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-162: American Association of Junior Colleges - Vocational and technical education at the junior college level, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-164: University of Colorado - Program in engineering design and economic evaluation, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-165: Joint Council on Economic Education, New York - Support for a monthly publication for the high schools, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-166: W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research - Study of the problem of measuring structural enemployment, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-169: State Agricultural University at Wageningen, Netherlands, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-171: Howard University - Faculty seminar on the problems of urbanization in developing countries, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-172: Boston College - Russian and East European Institute, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-173: American Association for the Advancement of Soviet Studies - Support for conference on problems of American cultural exchange with the U.S.S.R., 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-174: American Council on Education - Program for negro colleges - Projects for 1964-1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-175: International Labor Organization - Cost of living survey in Nyasaland, 1963 (Reel P-1039)
- E-178: United States Youth Council - All-South human relations youth conference, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-179: National Highway Users Conference, Inc. - Educational program for emergency highway transportation, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-180: Ithaca City School District - Technological advances in elementary classroom instruction, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-183: George Washington University - Implement an integrated program of education for government and business administration, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-184: University of Southern California - Institute for deans of engineering, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-186: Agricultural, Mechanical and Normal College, Pine Bluff, Arkansas, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-187: American Friends Service Committee - Program of leadership education in international affairs, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-188: University of Southern California - Overseas program of the USC professional schools, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-189: University of Pittsburgh - Inter-University research program in institution building, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-192: Trade Associates, Inc. - Development of new system of mass transportation, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-193: State Bar of California - Committee on group legal services, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-195: Union College - Strengthen the library facilities of the observatory, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-197: University of Pittsburgh - Summer college predatory program for culturally disadvantaged students, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-198: University of notre Dame - Study of the Catholic marriage advisory system in England, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-199: California Association of Secondary School Administrators - Study project on vocational education in secondary schools, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-200: American Public Health Association - Committee on Family and Population Planning, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-201: State University of New York (SUNY) Downstate Medical Center - Ultrastructural analysis of the early stages of implantation and embryonic development (Ralph M. Wynn, MD), 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-205: Foundation for Youth and Student Affairs, Inc. - Conference on training for African leadership, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-206: St. Louis University - Teacher education oriented to the urban setting, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-207: Fisk University - Proposed Three-year Master of Arts program for superior students at Fisk University, 1964 (Reel P-1039)
- E-208: Conservation Foundation - Applied human ecology in Central America, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-210: NAACP Legal Defense Fund - Program of training for civil rights lawyers, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-211: Georgetown University, Institute of Language and Linguistics - International conference on current research in empirical linguistics, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-213: San Diego State College Foundation - "Role of the secondary school in providing vocational skills and knowledge for American citizens", 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-215: San Jose State College (California State University, San Jose) - Study of learning to read (Patrick J. Ryan), 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-218: New York State, Divison of Housing and Community Renewal - Study on "Intergroup Living in Cooperative Housing- Impact on Families and Communities", 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-222: National Council on the Aging - Expanded program of activities by the American Association of Homes for the Aging (Reel P-1040)
- E-223: St. Albans School - International Seminars program, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-224: University of Wisconsin - New professional curriculum for teacher education, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-225: Improvement of Education and Training in Police Administration (Ford Foundation initiated), 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-226: Detroit Public Schools – Children's' Museum, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-227: Northwood Institute - audio visual devices and techniques at Northwood Institute, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-230: National Association of Independent Schools - Educational enrichment summer program, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-231: Carleton University - Study of Carleton University students, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-233: University of Wisconsin - Role of financial institutions in economic development, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- E-237: New York University - Summer law teaching training program, 1964 (Reel P-1040)
- NY-79: Unofficial Ambassadors Inc., 1953-1956 (Reel P-1040)
  Project "developing mobile museums representing various foreign countries. The museums would be staffed by nationals of the countries involved, and would visit various cities in the U.S.".